Sri Rama Gangadhar Veeraghanta

1602-1160, rue St-Mathieu, Montréal, Québec, H3H 2P4 veeraghanta.sriram@gmail.com, (514) 709-1160, https://vsriram.me/, Github, LinkedIn

Full Stack Developer

Profile

I am a passionate and self motivated developer with a good share of experience working with frameworks like **NextJS**, **React**, **Django**, **Phoenix**. I always aim to solve real-time problems using interactive solutions. In my years of experience handling multiple products, I strongly believe choosing right technologies/tools, best practices and architecture are necessary for building a reliable and scalable product. Experienced in architecting products in the field of **E-Commerce**, **E Learning**, **Real-Time Communications** and **Fintech**.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:Javascript, Python, Java, C, C++, ElixirFull Stack Frameworks:NextJS, Django, Flask, Express, PhoenixFront End Framework:ReactJS, Gatsby, VueJS, Jekyll, Angular

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, SQLite, FaunaDB

Mobile Development: Android, React Native

Services: Docker, Vagrant

Design Systems: Illustrator, Figma, Adobe XD

Education

Programming and Web Technologies Diploma, AEC

2019 - 2021

L'institut Supérieur d'Informatique Montreal, Quebec, Canada

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology, BTech

2016

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Kakinada Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh, India.

Work Experience

Soulpage IT Solutions

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Consulting Engineering Manager

Hyderabad, India

- Organize and Manage multiple teams and handle multiple projects at the same time.
- Create product workflows, user stories around the products, Handle scrum meetings, handle client meetings and make sure all teams work together for a common goal.
- Improve developer experience, Implementing design methodologies and handling deployments are some of the core responsibilities i have handled.
- Creating continuous integration pipelines for automated testing and continuous deployment pipeline are some of my core skills that helped the company a lot.

Feb 2019 - Jan 2021 WealthTab

Full Stack Developer Montreal. Canada

• Build scalable fintech applications, design interactive user interfaces using frameworks like NextJS, AngularJS and building scalable api servers in Laravel and Django.

- Project architecturing, implemented design methodologies that improve the amount of work done.
- Develop, Deploy and Maintain multiple projects at same time. Create scalable architecture using microservice architectures around the projects.
- Design and Development of frontend applications using REST APIs and deploying web applications on platforms like AWS, GCP and Digital Ocean are some of the core responsibilities.
- Minimize the technical gap between product designers and clients by explaining the complexity and coming up with realistic deadlines in client meetings.

Caravel.Al May 2017 - Nov 2018 Hyderabad, India

Head of Engineering

- Design and development of progressive web applications and single-page applications.
- Build interactive web and mobile applications using REST APIs.
- Lead development teams for products like Keats, SATnPaper and few other internal projects. Crafting design principles and programming practices internal to the company.
- Train interns and full-time employees on web designing and javascript frameworks.

Tuttor May 2016 - April 2017 Head of Design Hyderabad, india

- Design and development of interactive user interfaces and user experience using ReactJS.
- Design and development of intuitive classroom interfaces using WebRTC.
- Product designing, creating marketing design campaigns around product pages and taking responsibilities in various operations internal to the company.

Projects

LiberoMeet (NextJS, Elixir)

It is a video conferencing application using webrtc. Creating events and meetings around the conference rooms. It is a fully functional virtual meeting tool like GoogleMeet and Zoom with features like chat, notes and whiteboard inside the video room.

Role: Product Designer, Team lead and Engineering Lead, with a team of 10 members.

Reference Links: https://liberomeet.io/

AssetMatch - L'oreal Paris (NextJS, Django, Google Vision API)

An image matching application using google vision api. Designed a frontend application to upload image assets to match over the web using vision apis. Displaying results in the user dashboard with the data retrieved from vision api.

Role: Project Architect and Developer working alone.

KeatsApp (Django, ReactJS)

An interactive learning application for kids to learn to programme. Creating a learning environment for kids with attractive challenges using different learning methods.

Role: Product Designing, Frontend development lead, with a team of 6 members.

Reference Links: https://keats.app/

SATnPaper (Django, VueJS)

SATnPaper is a premium online platform for Indian students aspiring for undergraduate admissions to US colleges by training them for the ACT and SAT exam using mock tests.

Role: Product Designing, Frontend development lead, with a team of 4 members.

Reference Links: https://satnpaper.com/

ReactWorkflows (ReactJS-Library)

A react package for creating workflows about the react application using context api to create a common state dependency between the components and customizable UI elements. Helps to create step based form submission easy.

Role: solo developer working on a cool open source project.

Note: Planned to Release V1 by new year of 2021

Crate - Academic Project (NodeJS)

Providing interface and secure permission for users to access files locally using a local server that was deployed and tested in college. Working on converting this project into an NPM module for better accessibility.

Role: Team lead (academic project with 4 people)

Reference: https://github.com/sriramveeraghanta/crate

Collabcode (NodeJS, Operational Transformation)

Collaborative online text editor with syntax highlighter. Each user is provided with a random workspace that can be shared with others for collaboration. Currently refactoring the project Conflict Free Replicated Data Types.

Role: Personal Fun Time Project

Other Activities

ConvergeConf 2017

Infrastructure Chair

Led a team of 6 people for handling conference ticketing system, organizing food and snacks to participants, Issuing id cards and goodies to the participants, Handling auditorium sound system, lights for around two thousand students.

Andhra Pradesh Python Users Group (APPYUG)

Core Team Member

As a part of core team members, Organizing free workshops and meetups in various different colleges and companies. Giving talks to students in various colleges regarding the importance and simplicity of the python language.

References available upon request